<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Pradyumna Chatterjee</title><link href="https://pradyumnac.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pradyumnac.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pradyumnac.github.io/</id><updated>2019-09-24T15:55:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Hello World!</title><link href="https://pradyumnac.github.io/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-24T14:49:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-09-24T14:49:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Pradyumna Chatterjee</name></author><id>tag:pradyumnac.github.io,2019-09-24:/hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Introduction rants..&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Saying Hi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I have started blogs time and again. However, due to advances in technologies - Its now easier and cheaper than ever to host a pltform where you can capture and share your voice online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enter SSG ( Static Site Generators)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the technologically uninclined, Static Site generators are resource lite collection of web pages can be hosted on any file server. They dont need to run any server side logic. 
Thus, Hosting of any CDN, Dropbox, Amazon S3 or even git trepositories like github and gitlab is possible. alll side corganization is done before upload&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What to expect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything and everything! Being a person with an inclination to think ( Sometimes toomuch and unnecessarily), it becomes important to capture your thoughts somewhere. Think of this site as a Diary/Journal which is public facing. Only my honest opinions and thoughts - sometimes innovative, sometimes bland; someother time laconic and comprehensive, Some times naive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why should this interest me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, Most probably it wont. At least most of the time. The Topics I write are wde and far stretched to interest the most. However, You if are here, reading this blog, chances are you found some topic you were looking for and landed up here.&lt;br&gt;
There would perhaps be some recurring themes/topics I will write frequently about. If the following interest you, Who not read some more:&lt;br&gt;
* Technology
    * Python
    * Data Science &amp;amp; Statistics
    * Tutorials
    * Scripting
* Socialogy
* Productivity
* Religion &amp;amp; Spirituality
* Photography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where to next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were able to read through all these rants, perhaps have a look at the following articles? Might interest you , might not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also do check out my github repo whgere OI geerally script up utilities to bost daily productivity. Even The blog I am writing on is on a Python jupyter Notebook. 
Check out &lt;a href="https://github.com/pradyumnac/userpageblog"&gt;this github repo&lt;/a&gt; to know how I do it ( in the readme section)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="hello-world"></category><category term="introduction"></category></entry><entry><title>Voices from the Deep Void</title><link href="https://pradyumnac.github.io/voices-from-a-deep-void.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-18T22:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-09-24T15:55:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Pradyumna Chatterjee</name></author><id>tag:pradyumnac.github.io,2019-09-18:/voices-from-a-deep-void.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Free verse of Sorts&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;A Free Verse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sonic boom from the supersonic jets growls up&lt;br&gt;
Overpowering the voice of millions of ants&lt;br&gt;
Screaming at the top of their voices,&lt;br&gt;
Screaming in pain!&lt;br&gt;
Screams of agony and despair!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving a kilometer is a big deal&lt;br&gt;
Searching food for their community;&lt;br&gt;
Rations of the imminent winter..&lt;br&gt;
A millions of tireless feet - feets scuttering to stock piles &lt;br&gt;
That gets them through a ghastly cold;&lt;br&gt;
They have their burrows not so deep in the ground&lt;br&gt;
Sheltering under the permafrost - six months a pop!   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still the booms growls &lt;br&gt;
The jet travelling kilometers in a matter of minutes!&lt;br&gt;
The splurge of champagne on faces of a select few.&lt;br&gt;
Cavier and roasted beef;&lt;br&gt;
Excesses in all their own right!&lt;br&gt;
Who gets to thrive?    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crashing sound is witnessed hunderds of miles across!&lt;br&gt;
Leading clouds of empty void crashing onto itself.&lt;br&gt;
Who do you hear o king?
Whose voices ring thy mortal eardrums?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do the ants have any less right &lt;br&gt;
Over lands, their mountains and valleys and fields? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Who takes a call on&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
WHAT IS PROGRESS? &lt;br&gt;
Some green numbers on the blips of a gigantic screen &lt;br&gt;
Or the voices of netherland left untold?    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gorges from the void grows deeper&lt;br&gt;
Fathoms at a time unflickered; &lt;br&gt;
What do you do about these fathoms?&lt;br&gt;
What will make these two ends meet??  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Says a scientist with a towel around his waist,&lt;br&gt;
emerging from a giant hot tub of bath:  &lt;br&gt;
"I will put in a log of a log to the signal&lt;br&gt;
That makes the curves stratight and their voices neat!"  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet,&lt;br&gt;
The axe looms high&lt;br&gt;
Hanging by a tout string of obstinacy;&lt;br&gt;
What is hearing but not understanding? &lt;br&gt;
What is understanding but not empathy??  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="poetry"></category><category term="Philosophy"></category></entry></feed>